<Document>
# Brotherhood of Steel

The Brotherhood of Steel is a post-war military order founded by U.S. Army Captain Roger Maxson after he led his troops to defy the government and fortify a missile silo in California. Dedicating themselves to collecting, preserving, and controlling pre-war technology, they believe that advanced weapons and energy systems in untrained hands threaten any chance of lasting civilization.

Their rigid chain of command mirrors military hierarchy. Obedience and rank define everything within a Brotherhood chapter.

## Philosophy

The Brotherhood views pre-war technology as too valuable and too dangerous for untrained hands. Outsiders are tolerated only when useful. Internally, rank is absolute — orders flow downward and are followed without question.

## Chain of Command

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Elder[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Elders represent the pinnacle of Brotherhood command. Most chapters are ruled by a council, though regional field chapters often answer to a single commanding Elder. Reaching this rank requires decades of service and is typically held for life. Notable Elders include Elder Maxson of the West Coast chapter and Elder Arthur Maxson of the East Coast Brotherhood.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Command the chapter. Technology acquisitions, alliances, and military operations require your authorization. Other factions will seek your ear first — or avoid you entirely.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Paladin[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Paladins are the Brotherhood's elite warriors — veterans who have earned the right to don full power armor and wield the chapter's most advanced weapons. They lead strike teams and serve as field commanders, representing the Brotherhood's ideal of what a soldier should be. Paladins like Paladin Danse of the East Coast chapter are among the most respected figures the Brotherhood produces.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Lead combat operations and enforce Brotherhood authority in the field. You are the Elder's arm. Wherever you go, the chapter's will follows.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Knight[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Knights form the core of Brotherhood military might — fully inducted members who serve as both combatants and technicians, maintaining and operating the chapter's arsenal. The Knight order carries internal ranks — Knight, Knight Sergeant, Knight Captain, Knight Commander — each carrying greater responsibility and better access to equipment.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Protect Brotherhood territory, maintain weapons and armor, and carry out orders from Paladins and above. You are the Brotherhood's backbone in any engagement.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Scribe[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Scribes are the Brotherhood's scholars and technicians. While they rarely fight, they are critical to any chapter's survival — cataloguing pre-war technology, maintaining advanced equipment, and researching new applications for recovered devices. Without Scribes, recovered technology becomes useless relics. Senior Scribes hold significant influence despite their non-combat role.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Research, repair, and document Brotherhood technology. Your knowledge protects assets that no amount of force could replace. When the chapter finds something new, it comes to you.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Initiate[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Initiates are the newest members of the Brotherhood — recruits accepted into the order but not yet proven. In lore, Initiates undergo years of training before advancement is even considered. They receive basic equipment and are assigned support roles under supervision. Only those who demonstrate genuine discipline and competence advance beyond this rank.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Follow orders, learn the Brotherhood's ways, and prove your worth. You will be assigned the most demanding and least glamorous duties — and perform them without complaint.
</Box>

## Relations

The Brotherhood does not negotiate from weakness. They will demand technology from those who possess it and offer protection — or threat — in exchange. The NCR and Brotherhood share one of the most storied rivalries in the Wasteland, having fought the bitter NCR-Brotherhood War at Helios One. If both factions are present in the same region, open conflict is never far away.
</Document>
