<Document>
# Crafting System Guide

Welcome to the crafting system guide! This guide will help you understand how to create items using blueprints, workbenches, and various tools. Crafting is an important part of survival in the Wasteland.

Let's dive into the details!

## Crafting Basics

Crafting is the process of creating items using blueprints, resources, and tools. Each blueprint specifies the required materials, tools, and type of workbench. Here's how it works:

1. Blueprints: Blueprints are instructions for crafting. They specify the required resources, tools, and type of workbench.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorT45Blueprint"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponSniper556TribalBlueprint"/>
</Box>

2. Workbenches: Different items require different workbenches. For example, crafting power armor may require a power armor workbench.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WorkbenchStation"/>
</Box>

3. Resources: Crafting requires specific resources. These can be raw materials, scrap components, or even other crafted items.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ScrapElectronic"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14JunkGunpartsAdvancedFrame"/>
</Box>

4. Tools: Some recipes require tools such as screwdrivers, wrenches, or welding equipment. These tools are not consumed but are necessary to complete the process.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14Screwdriver"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14Welder"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14Wrench"/>
</Box>

5. Faction Restrictions: Some blueprints are only available to certain factions. Make sure your faction affiliation allows you to use the required recipes.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14DecorationFlagNCR"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14FlagWallWesternBrotherhood"/>
</Box>

## Crafting Process

Step-by-step guide to creating an item:

1. Find a Blueprint: Blueprints can be found in the world, purchased from traders, or obtained as rewards. Each blueprint specifies the item being created and crafting requirements.

2. Gather Resources: Check what resources are needed for the blueprint and collect them in the exact quantity.

3. Find an Appropriate Workbench: Find a workbench that matches the recipe. For example, crafting power armor will require a power armor workbench.

4. Start Crafting: Approach the workbench, open the crafting interface, select the needed blueprint, and confirm item creation.

5. Done!: If everything is done correctly, you will receive a new item. It will now be in your inventory or appear next to the workbench.

## Available Blueprints

Blueprints are found by exploring the Wasteland, looting enemies, or trading with faction vendors. Click any blueprint entry to see its full crafting requirements.

### Brotherhood of Steel

Power armor restoration and Brotherhood gear blueprints. Typically found in BoS patrols and bunkers.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorT45Blueprint" Caption="T-45 Power Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorT60TeslaBlueprint" Caption="T-60 Tesla Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterMBoSInitiateArmorBlueprint" Caption="BoS Initiate Armor"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterMidwestArmorBlueprint" Caption="Midwest Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterMidwestArmorMK2Blueprint" Caption="Midwest Armor MK2"/>
</Box>

### NCR

New California Republic military armor and power armor restoration blueprints. Found in NCR camps and quartermaster caches.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorT45NCRBlueprint" Caption="T-45 NCR Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorT51NCRBlueprint" Caption="T-51 NCR Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorT60NCRBlueprint" Caption="T-60 NCR Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorRaiderBlueprint" Caption="Raider Power Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterPowerArmorAdvanced1NCRBlueprint" Caption="Advanced NCR Armor"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterNCRVestDesertBlueprint" Caption="NCR Desert Vest"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterNCRCombatArmorBlueprint" Caption="NCR Combat Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterNCRCombatArmorMK2Blueprint" Caption="NCR Combat Armor MK2"/>
</Box>

### Legion

Caesar's Legion armor blueprints. Recovered from Legion outposts and veteran centurions.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterLegionnaireBaseArmorBlueprint" Caption="Legionnaire Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterLegionnaireVeteranArmorBlueprint" Caption="Veteran Legionnaire Armor"/>
</Box>

### Tribal

Handcrafted tribal weapons and armor blueprints. Traded by tribal communities or found in Wasteland camps.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponRevolver45-70HandcannonBlueprint" Caption="Handcannon"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponRevolver44TribalBlueprint" Caption="Tribal Handgun"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ModificationkitRevolver44TribalBlueprint" Caption="Revolver Upgrade Kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ModificationkitRevolver44TribalUpgradedBlueprint" Caption="Revolver Upgrade Extra Kit"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponSniper556TribalBlueprint" Caption="Tribal Rifle"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponSniper556TribalUpgradedBlueprint" Caption="Tribal Assault Rifle"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterCombatTribalBlueprint" Caption="Tribal Combat Armor"/>
</Box>

### Miscellaneous

Faction-neutral or independently produced blueprints available to any skilled crafter.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponLaserRevolverBlueprint" Caption="Laser Revolver"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponLaserRifleMakeshiftBlueprint" Caption="Makeshift Laser Rifle"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14WeaponRifle556PipeBlueprint" Caption="Pipe Rifle (.556)"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterCombatArmorBlueprint" Caption="Combat Armor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="N14ClothingOuterCombatArmorMK2Blueprint" Caption="Combat Armor MK2"/>
</Box>

Good luck with your crafting. With the right blueprints, tools, and resources, you will be able to create items that will help you survive and thrive in this harsh world.
</Document>
