<Document>
# Guide to Townsfolk

The townsfolk of Oasis are the people who chose to stop moving and build something worth defending. Farmers, traders, lawmen, and craftspeople — they are the backbone of local civilization in the Wasteland.

No faction has a higher stake in the outcome of every encounter. When larger factions come demanding taxes, technology, or submission, it is the Mayor who negotiates and the townspeople who live with every consequence. Their survival depends on each other.

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Mayor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Settlement leaders are a recurring archetype in Fallout — from Mayor MacCready of Little Lamplight to the various Mayors of Diamond City. They hold authority through community trust rather than military power, making their position inherently fragile. Effective Mayors in Fallout are skilled negotiators and reluctant politicians — the last line of defense between their town and the factions circling it.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Lead Oasis. Coordinate with the Sheriff on security and negotiate with outside factions on behalf of your people. Every deal you make has consequences for every person in town.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Sheriff[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] The wasteland Sheriff is a classic Fallout institution — figures like Sheriff Simms of Megaton or Sheriff Meyers represent the thin line between a functioning settlement and chaos. Most Sheriffs hold authority through reputation and force of will as much as any badge. When the Sheriff stops inspiring confidence, the badge stops meaning anything.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Protect Oasis from threats internal and external. Manage your deputies, keep the peace, and work alongside the Mayor on anything that touches both law and politics. What your badge means to this town is entirely up to how you carry it.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Deputy[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Deputies in Fallout settlements are the Sheriff's closest allies — the people trusted with enforcing the law when the Sheriff cannot be everywhere. A dependable deputy is a lifeline; a corrupt one is a crisis. In small communities, personal character matters more than formal authority.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Support the Sheriff. Enforce order, investigate problems, and step up when the Sheriff is unavailable. Your loyalty to the badge — and the people it's supposed to protect — defines what law means in Oasis.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Shopkeeper[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Every functioning Fallout settlement has its merchant soul — from Moira Brown of Craterside Supply to Chet's store in Goodneighbor. Shopkeepers are often the best-informed people in any town; trade brings information, and information is as valuable as caps. They are also economically among the most critical people in the settlement.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Stock and run the town's store. Trade with travelers, manage inventory, and keep the local economy moving. You may not carry a weapon to war, but caps talk — and yours talk loudly.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Mechanic[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Skilled engineers are among the most valued individuals in any wasteland settlement. Those who can repair power armor, coax generators back to life, or jury-rig broken weapons are treated like treasures. Without a mechanic, a settlement slowly degrades into helplessness. The Atom Cats of the Commonwealth show how much cultural weight technical skill carries in the post-war world.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Repair and maintain the settlement's critical equipment — weapons, armor, robots, and machinery. Craft new items for the town's defense or for sale to travelers. When something breaks, everyone comes to you.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Doctor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Wasteland doctors run the full spectrum from fully trained pre-war physicians to self-taught practitioners with a medical bag and a lot of confidence. Even the questionable ones — like Doc Mitchell in Goodsprings, who pulled the Courier back from the grave with improvised tools — are treated as community treasures. Where there is no doctor, people die of wounds that any proper clinic could have treated.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Provide medical care to townsfolk and travelers. Charge for your services or give them freely — that is your call. Your skills will be needed before the round ends, regardless of how peacefully things start.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Townsperson[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Ordinary settlers are the foundation of every functioning wasteland community. They do the work that keeps people fed, watered, clothed, and sheltered — and they are the ones with the most to lose when a faction decides to "liberate" or "tax" or "cleanse" their home. In Fallout, the fate of ordinary people is ultimately what every major storyline comes down to.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Work the land, tend animals, craft goods, and do what your town needs to stay alive. You are not a soldier — but the Wasteland has a way of making everyone a fighter eventually.
</Box>
</Document>